firstName: "Grayson", lastName: "Gilmore"

Email gilmoreg@live.com

Folio

http://gilmoreg.com

GitHub

https://github.com/gilmoreg

LinkedIn

/in/graysongilmore

Profile

Full-stack developer skilled in writing, clean, testable Javascript. Experienced with Node, MongoDB, Python, React, jQuery, vanilla JavaScript, and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. Experienced with modern tooling and excited to pick up the right tools for the job.

Skill Set

Server Side: Node.js, Express, Python Flask and Django, MongoDB, Passport, GraphQL, Serverless

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap, Responsive design

Testing: Jest, Mocha, Chai, Enzyme

DevOps: Heroku, Docker, Travis CI, AWS Lightsail, Digital Ocean

Projects

Condictor • http://condictor.gilmoreg.com • Github repo

A lightweight helpdesk issue tracker. Built with Node, GraphQL, MongoDB, and React/Redux.

Referendus • http://referendus.herokuapp.com • Github repo

A lightweight reference/bibliography manager. Built with Node, MongoDB, Passport, and Angular 4.

Lego Collector • https://gilmoreg.github.io/legocollector • Github repo

Track Amazon stock levels for lego sets. Built with Python, Flask, Postgres, and React/Redux.

Steam Battle • http://steam-battle.gilmoreg.com • Github repo

Compare Steam profiles and declare a winner! Built with React/Redux and Google Cloud Functions.

Open Source

Habitica: Contributed PRs to increase test coverage

Education

Thinkful • Fullstack Web Development, Jan - May 2017

Completed intensive, six-month course on modern full-stack JavaScript development. Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

Boston College • Ph.D., Political Science, 2009 - 2015

Work History

Northern Illinois University • Visiting Assistant Professor, 2016 - 2017

Developed and taught both graduate and undergraduate courses, mentored graduate students.

Boston College • John Marshall Postdoctoral Fellow, 2015 - 2016

Developed and maintained the website for the John Marshall Project (Adobe Experience Manager). Jumpstarted and directed the JMP Undergraduate Fellowship program. Taught freshman and junior level undergraduate courses.

American Fiber Systems • Network Operations Technician, 2003 - 2008

Provided network monitoring and troubleshooting for a nationwide fiber optic network. CCNA and Network+ certified.